DARWIN ANDERSON Software Developer

Personal Information

PHONE

256-275-1628

EMAIL

☑ darwin@darwin.ovh

WEBSITE

darwin.ovh

GITHUB

github.com/Faladis

PROFICIENCIES

Language Proficiencies

- HTML 5 / CSS / SASS
- PHP (Procedural & OOP)
- MYSQL
- Javascript
- AngularJS
- AJAX
- SOAP/REST

SKILL PROFICIENCIES

- Solution Analysis
- UI/UX Design
- API design
- Full-Stack Deployment
- Database Administration
- Project Planning and Management

Software Developer with five years of experience specializing in web development, data processing, and software suite development for municipal and government offices. I have developed and implemented API modules, accounting systems, payment processing modules, database schemas, and entire site redesigns for scales both small and large scale projects. My greatest strengths are my analytical and organizational skills, which enable me to properly plan projects with AGILE methodologies in mind while remaining framework agnostic.

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

2013 - CURRENT

 Developed tools for internal administration and customer support usage

- Implemented updates to legacy systems to bring them up to security and W3C standards
- Developed public-facing websites for municipal offices
- Planned and developed projects of various scopes

MAJOR PROJECTS

2014 - 2015

2015 - ongoing

REPORT OVERHAUL - LEAD DEVELOPER

IMS Enterprises, Inc. - Florence, AL

Problem: Several municipal offices were having difficulty distinguishing information on sales reports at a glance. When surveyed, not all offices wished to have distinguishing characteristics added to their reports.

Solution: Several additional configuration options were added to all municipal installs to allow for reports to be redesigned into a single, uniform format as well as toggle between color-themed reports and standard reports. All reports were modified to add classes to distinguishing elements, which would show colored rows on reports where the config option was enabled.

COUNTY SITE DEVELOPMENT - LEAD DEVELOPER

Problem: As several municipal offices changed to our service, their prior services refused to maintain their public facing websites.

Solution: This issue was used to open a dialog with our municipal clients, offering them the ability to redesign their websites in a manner that they wanted. At the same time, the existing sites were either converted from unmaintained Joomla/Wordpress sites or redesigned entirely as HTML, CSS, & PHP based websites. The files were made immutable, and hosted on secure servers with SSH access only.

Additional Details: In 2017, most sites hosted in this manner were moved from standalone VM software to secure docker containers with git hooks to pull from internal repositories. This made updating and maintaining the sites faster and much easier.

47th Infantry Reunion Website - Project Lead

Problem: The 47th Infantry Reunion Website needed several updates and new systems implemented while maintaining as much legacy support as possible.

Solution: The site was first assessed for which pages needed to be redesigned immediate and which systems needed to be updated. Reunions were held every two years - for the 2016 reunion, there was enough time to implement a few quality updates and add basic payment processing systems(eCheck).

In late 2016, an entire modular redesign of the registration system was designed and implemented over the course of 2017. The system was designed in AngularJS with AJAX queries to a PHP based API. This allowed users to update their registration and see the changes in realtime via MVC methodologies. Once registration was complete, they were transferred to a PCI secure payment gateway(TLS 1.2) to process credit card and echeck payments. Transaction details were recorded in various states(incomplete, success, fail), and systems were put in place for registrants to pay for additional events, register additional guests, request refunds, and cancel their registration. Additional tools for badge generation, reports, and on-site tools were developed as well.

2015 - ongoing

EDUCATION

2009 - 2011

Northwest Shoals Community College

Associates of Applied Science - Computer Science

REFERENCES AVAILABLE UPON REQUEST

THIS RESUME WAS DESIGNED WITH HTML & CSS. PLEASE VISIT DARWIN.OVH/RESUME FOR AN ONLINE VERSION.